Russell M. Logie Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Russell M. Logie Archives
1891-1933
IPAR.001080
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
5
The archives of Russell M. Logie including maps and notebooks encompassing his time at Yale.
Logie, Russell Moore
Biographical Sketch
Yale Grad School ?34; Employer: Peabody Museum. Elected as a member of the Paleontological Society in 1933.
Description of the Material
Primarily USGS 7.5" topographic quadrangle maps covering New York and eastern Pennsylvania published between 1891 and 1933. Also a sketch map of New York showing the location of many localities. Also four field notebooks from New York dated 1931-1933; assorted stratigraphic sections, charts and reports; and correspondence.
Connecticut; New York; USA; Maps; Field notebooks; Correspondence; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, 1891-1933; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Topographic Maps of NY, PA & NJ.
  - 1890-1900., 001084
    - Topographic map. Easton, PA-NJ 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1891; 001837
    - Topographic map. Pottsville, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1891; 001842
    - Topographic map. Delaware Water Gap, PA-NJ 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1893; 001836
    - Topographic map. Durham, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1894; 001816
    - Topographic map. Allentown, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1894; 001838
    - Topographic map. Amsterdam, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1895; 001813
    - Topographic map. Catskill, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1895; 001819
    - Topographic map. Medina, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1897; 001778
    - Topographic map. Albion, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1897; 001780
    - Topographic map. Syracuse, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1898; 001798
    - Topographic map. Oriskany, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1898; 001804
    - Topographic map. Rhinebeck, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1898; 001823
    - Topographic map. Cazenovia, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1899; 001801
    - Topographic map. Harrisburg, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1899; 001844
    - Topographic map. Macedon, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001786
    - Topographic map. Macedon, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001787
    - Topographic map. Baldwinsville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001796
    - Topographic map. Tully, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001799
    - Topographic map. Schoharie, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1900; 001812
  - 1901-1910., 001085
    - Topographic map. Niagara Falls, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001773
    - Topographic map. Tonawanda, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001774
    - Topographic map. Buffalo, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001775
    - Topographic map. Lockport, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001776
    - Topographic map. West Point, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1901; 001831
    - Topographic map. Palmyra, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001790
    - Topographic map. Phelps, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001791
    - Topographic map. Clyde, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001792
    - Topographic map. Geneva, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001793
    - Topographic map. Weedsport, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001794
    - Topographic map. Auburn, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001795
    - Topographic map. Skaneateles, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001797
    - Topographic map. Chittenango, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001800
    - Topographic map. Oneida, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001802
    - Topographic map. Morrisville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001803
    - Topographic map. Canajoharie, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001809
    - Topographic map. Fonda, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001811
    - Topographic map. Tarrytown, NY-NJ 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001834
    - Topographic map. Slatington, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1902; 001839
    - Topographic map. Canandaigua, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001788
    - Topographic map. Canandaigua, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001789
    - Topographic map. Little Falla, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001807
    - Topographic map. Richfield Springs, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001808
    - Topographic map. Berne, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001814
    - Topographic map. Albany, NY 15 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001815
    - Topographic map. Kaaterskill, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001818
    - Topographic map. Rosendale, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001821
    - Topographic map. Rosendale, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001822
    - Topographic map. Newburgh, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001826
    - Topographic map. Newburgh, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001827
    - Topographic map. Poughkeepsie, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001828
    - Topographic map. Paterson, NJ-NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1903; 001835
    - Topographic map. Batavia, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001781
    - Topographic map. Brockport, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001782
    - Topographic map. Caledonia, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001783
    - Topographic map. Honeoye, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001785
    - Topographic map. Richmondville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1904; 001810
    - Topographic map. Depew, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1905; 001777
    - Topographic map. Attica, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1905; 001779
    - Topographic map. Slide Mountain, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1905; 001820
    - Topographic map. Ellenville, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1906; 001825
    - Topographic map. Sangerfield, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1907; 001805
    - Topographic map. Winfield, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1907; 001806
    - Topographic map. New Bloomfield, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1907; 001845
    - Topographic map. Millerstown, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1907; 001846
    - Topographic map. Port Jervis, NY-NJ-PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1908; 001829
    - Topographic map. Schunemunk, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1908; 001830
    - Topographic map. Bellefonte, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1909; 001848
    - Topographic map. Greenwood Lake, NJ-NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1910; 001832
    - Topographic map. Ramapo, NY-NJ 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1910; 001833
  - 1911-1920., 001086
    - Topographic map. Monticello, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1911; 001824
    - Topographic map. Hamburg, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1911; 001841
    - Topographic map. Reading, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1915; 001843
    - Topographic map. Rochester, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1920; 001784
  - 1921-1933., 001087
    - Topographic map. Mauch Chunk, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1924; 001840
    - Topographic map. Lewistown, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1927; 001847
    - Topographic map. Coxsackie, NY 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1929; 001817
    - Topographic map. Centre Hall, PA 7.5 Quad. (1: 62500). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1929; 001849
  - Miscellaneous Maps. Sketchings and outlines of maps., 001088
    - Sketch Map of New York with localities: New York; Dunbar index map, 1933; 000262
    - Logie tracing of New York (1: 1000000). Logie, R.M.: Outline tracing., 001772
- Field Notebooks, 1931-1933; Series II
  Field Notebooks from New York.
  - 1931., 001089
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1931; 000059
  - 1932., 001090
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1932; 000060
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1932; 000061
  - 1933., 001091
    - Notebook. Field Notebook: New York., 1933; 000062
    - Notebook with localities at end: New York. 1931, 1932, 1933, 000259
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  Miscellaneous Archives including correspondence and Stratigraphic information.
  - Correspondence., 001093
    - Correspondence, 000263
  - Stratigraphic Information. Stratigraphic charts and reports., 001092
    - Stratigraphic sections: New York. 1931, 1932, 1933, 000173
    - Stratigraphy Reports: New York., 1933; 000260
    - Stratigraphy Charts & Faunal Lists: New York., 1933; 000261
    - Geologic Cross Sections of the Silurian & Devonian of New York State:., 1933; 000264
    - Stratigraphy of the Manlius Group of New York (unpublished manuscript for Yale dissertation -- never submitted): New York., 1933; 000294